<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>K5924&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/</link>
        <description>Recent content on K5924&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:45:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k5924.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Elevation</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/elevation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:45:23 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/elevation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are provided with a working application that searches a raster of elevation data for regions of relative flatness. The raster is an image in which each pixel represents an elevation for a point on the terrain. The application can be imagined to be searching for potential landing sites for an aircraft or spacecraft of some kind.
rgbelevation contains example images to use with the program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;searchuienhancement&#34;&gt;SearchUIEnhancement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parallelisation&#34;&gt;Parallelisation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;considerations&#34;&gt;Considerations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All code must implement thread-safety correctly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;languages-and-tools&#34;&gt;Languages and Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Vault</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/the-vault/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:40:38 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/the-vault/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an offline password manager as most online password managers store a users information on centralized servers. This gives an end user the ability to take control of how there data is being used and allows end users&#39; to keep hold of their private data whilst interacting with a password manager with an easy to use interface. This project was made for coursework while i was in my 2nd Year of studying Computer Science at LSBU for the Software Engineering module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are compiling the code from source then ensure that python is installed on the machine with pip added to Path in the environment variables on windows. Through pip Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If pycryptodome fails to install, try running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then re-run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should install pycryptodome and PyQt5 for an end user to modify how the software works.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Additionally, you could run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will give you PyQt tools such as designer which will allow you to create the user interface via a drag an drop program.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
To export the interface that you have created in Qt Designer as a python file, Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or to get the interface you made as a python file that you want to run without another file to setup the interface run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demo&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mEqxIAc4rQM&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.youtube.com/vi/mEqxIAc4rQM/0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Demonstration Video&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>DiscreteMaths</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/discretemaths/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:35:03 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/discretemaths/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;CourseWork for Discrete Mathematics&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
The write up will be uploaded to this branch when the coursework has been marked&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
The file titled linear programming problem.ipynb is an anaconda notebook that i used to run all of the python scripts i have made.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lpp&#34;&gt;LPP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file titled lpp.py is the program i used to build the linear programming graphs of each individual edge in the tree.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;graph-theory&#34;&gt;Graph Theory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file titled dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algo.py is the algorithm used in the graph theory section&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;statistics&#34;&gt;Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic information files and the pdf files with the csv&amp;rsquo;s are used in this section for the boxplots, gaussian distributions and the probability density functions&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Choosing a programming language</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/choosing-a-programming-language/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 03:19:08 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/choosing-a-programming-language/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I will be talking about high level languages I think this post applies to all types of programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When programming everyone struggles to choose a specific programming language to code in but choosing a language to code in is easier than it seems. In my experience choosing a language mainly depends on what you want to do for the coding project you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if you are making a CLI application, there is no need to use a language like python or java as it adds unnecessary overhead to the application. Although it may be easier to code in python as you wont have to write as much code, in terms of speed of compilation times for large applications and when comparing file sizes, c is far better for command line applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were making a gui application, it is far easier using Java, C++ or Python. In this scenario I would select C++ for faster compilation times than Java and Python. If I was more focused on releasing an application quickly I would choose Python as it would use less lines of code than in C++. If I want the best of both worlds I would use Java as it is considerably faster than Python and handles memory management for you unlike in C++. The pitfall of Java is that it compiles in a slower time than C++ and would take longer to code than a Python program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For cross platform applications you have a choice between flutter, react native and xamarin. I haven&amp;rsquo;t included any frameworks which don&amp;rsquo;t offer native application development as they are considerably slower when used on a device. In this scenario it depends entirely on which programming languages you have familiarity with. React Native is for developers with extensive knowledge in React or JavaScript while flutter is very similar to Java. Xamarin is written in C# so it is most suitable for C# developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For game development, I would recommend using a game engine as they are easier to use than making your own engine and saves time. If you are first starting out I would recommend making a game in python using the pygame library and then move onto Unity, Godot or Unreal Engine. If its a 3D game then use Unity or Unreal Engine but if its a 2D game use Godot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although you may have familiarity with a specific language don&amp;rsquo;t let that deter you from learning others as all of these languages and frameworks can be learnt within a couple of months to a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main takeaway from this is choose a language that is optimized for the program your developing. If you prioritize speed when developing use a relatively high level language. If you prioritize the overall package size of the application, use a low level language as you can write a lot more code in a smaller digital footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What application are you making?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When do you have to deliver the application by?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many people will be working on the project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What programming languages are you familiar with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a list of languages which you could use then go down the list of questions while filtering out the languages which aren&amp;rsquo;t suitable for your application, then it will be considerably easier to choose what language to use. If you are still stuck there is no harm in trying both out and choosing the one you like coding in better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How Investing Works</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-investing-works/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:17:01 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-investing-works/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recommend a student account as there are many deals on overdrafts that students can get and many banks provide students incentives to use their student account, if you already have a bank account you can most likely just upgrade your account to a student account with your current bank either over the phone or in branch, this will not affect your bank account details so if you are being paid by student finance into this account their shouldn’t be an issue with the payments going into the account. One of these deals could be cash, larger overdrafts, higher interest on any money in these accounts or railcards for transportation in specific zones in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply for a credit card. If you get a credit card and put your mobile phone plan on their or a subscription on there and pay off the balance in full every month your credit score will surely increase. I was sceptical at first but this has improved my credit score tremendously and will allow me to get a mortgage or a loan in the future if I need to. I would recommend the credit club website created by money savings expert as it can tell you your credit score and will recommend credit cards that you can apply for. A mobile contract goes on your credit report but in my opinion, you could save more getting a credit card and paying off your mobile plan charged to the credit card rather than paying off a mobile phone contract which will cost more monthly. There are 2 rules to remember when dealing with credit cards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t carry a balance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t withdraw cash with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t carry a balance only applies to if the credit card is 0% interest where carrying a balance each month won’t increase the outstanding balance on the card, credit card companies are unlikely to give theses to students without any credit history so a normal credit card will most likely be issued to you which has a high-interest rate which will increase the overall balance on the card if you don’t pay it off in full every month. This is how credit card companies make money, as people don’t pay off their credit cards. Secondly, you shouldn’t withdraw cash on a credit card because credit cards have hidden charges for withdrawing cash, if you were to withdraw £10 at an ATM, either a fixed amount will be charged to you or a percentage of the money you withdraw will be charged to you so it’s easier to remember not to withdraw cash as either way you will get charged for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s talk about cash ISAs. These are basically savings accounts that you don’t pay tax on. You can put up to £20000 into ISAs each tax year from the age of 16 so that means £20000 split between all of the ISAs that you have opened in that tax year (a tax year is from the 6th of April to the 5th of April). As a cash ISA is basically a savings account, I recommend using this as an emergency fund. That means this account should have enough to cover at least 3-6 months of your total expenses in case anything happens. You should start by trying to build up this account each month so that when you have a job in the future, you get used to saving money and having enough money saved up that if you were to get fired, you would have enough saved that if it took a while for you to look for another job you could still survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I’m going to talk about LISAs (lifetime ISAs). They are used as a way for individuals to buy property in the future or for retirement but it can’t be used for anything else and you can only pay in up to £4000 each year into the LISA. They are either stored as cash LISAs or stocks and shares LISAs. I recommend that if you are looking to buy a house in the next 10 years use a cash LISA as you are able to get to the funds easily when buying a home. If you plan to buy a home after 10 years, I would recommend a stocks and shares LISA as the stock market will outperform any interest you could get on a cash LISA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also stocks and shares ISAs which let you invest in the stock market. If you are unsure of what platform to use, I recommend wealthify, if you don’t have a lot of money to spare or nutmeg which are both Robo-investors which invest in funds on your behalf. These services will allow you to learn about investing and will help you understand how investing works. When using wealthify and nutmeg I would recommend setting your choice to the highest risk level so that if the stock market increases the money you have in the stock market will also increase greatly. I also recommend staying away from the ethical investment choice as these have higher fees than the original investment choice. For nutmeg, I would also recommend sticking to fixed allocation to reduce the fees taken by the platform to invest on your behalf. If you feel more confident with your investment choices, I would recommend using a free broker like trading 212 as they offer stocks and shares ISAs without the need to pay a fee to invest in the stock market and you can invest in as little as £1. For information on what to invest in on trading 212, I would either recommend investing in a fund named VWRL or go on moneyunshackled.com and follow their portfolio distributions to own the world. Investing in funds lets you invest in multiple companies without having to buy a full share of each company. The stock market can be very volatile so invest only what you are comfortable losing, however, the likelihood of the stock market not recovering is very slim which is why I still see this as a good investment choice. This account should be seen as a long-term investment so try not to dip into this pot, try to use the cash ISA for any money you need desperately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final type of ISA is an Innovative Finance ISA. This is an ISA that essentially lends your money to companies, businesses or people so that you can gain interest on the money you put in. This is like giving out loans but instead of the bank doing this, the company you use to handle your innovative finance ISA match the money you put into your account to a person which wants to borrow that money. Cash, stocks and shares and lifetime ISAs are all covered by the FSCS which basically means that if the company holding your money goes bust, you can claim up to £85000 worth of money that you hold with these companies but for an innovative finance ISA, there is no FSCS protection so choose the company that you hold this ISA with wisely. This account is the only account that I highly advise against as, unlike the stock market where you can guarantee that the stock market as a whole will recover, with an innovative finance ISA if the company managing this ISA goes bust you have lost all the money you have put into this account and you can’t get it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For cash ISAs, Lifetime ISAs and innovative finance ISAs I recommend looking at money-saving experts’ website for their recommendation on the best interest rates you can get for each account. If you are unsure of where to put your money I would not use innovative finance ISAs and I would stick to the others detailed in this book, however, if you choose to use an innovate finance ISA I recommend only putting less than 5% of your maintenance loan in this account each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, let’s talk about cryptocurrency. I don’t recommend investing in cryptocurrency if you are not sure what cryptocurrency is look, into cryptocurrency investing through r/UKPersonalFinance or research into the topic. For simplicity, I will state that cryptocurrency shouldn’t be seen as a place to hold assets in a stable environment as cryptocurrency is very volatile. If you choose to invest in cryptocurrency, I recommend using Coinbase or Binance as they are the most reputable and when investing in cryptocurrency please use a two-factor authentication app to secure your account. If you choose to invest in cryptocurrency, I recommend investing less than 5% of your maintenance loan each year with a portfolio weighting of 50% Bitcoin, 40% Ethereum and 10% in altcoins of your choice. Personally, I started investing in cryptocurrency as the stock market was quite volatile in the past couple of months but I wouldn’t recommend this for an average student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a monthly budget of £500 and your total expenses come to £300, you could save £200 a month. I recommend £100 into your stocks and shares ISA and £50 into your cash ISA and LISA. If you choose to open an innovative finance ISA I would reduce the £50 into a LISA to £40 into a LISA and £10 into an innovative finance ISA. However, if you also decide to try cryptocurrency, I recommend putting £25 into your LISA and putting £12.50 into both your innovative finance ISA and cryptocurrency. Depending on your circumstance you could place more or less money into these accounts and depending on your risk appetite you may choose to invest in cryptocurrencies and an innovative finance ISA or to invest more in the stock market but this depends on your financial situation and how you feel about each of these investments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to Budget</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-budget/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:14:43 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-budget/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You need to set up a budget if you expect to have your maintenance last until the end of the year. I recommend either using apps or spreadsheets. The apps I would recommend are Emma or Money Dashboard. They both offer the same features as they track how much you spend and pulls all or most of your financial accounts into a single place so you can view all of the money coming in and going out each month. The main differences between the apps are that Emma is better looking whilst Money Dashboard is more customizable. They also help you to set up budgets and give you notifications for transactions. Emma is more helpful in giving you ways to improve your spending by allowing you to compare prices for bills and by giving your insight into what accounts you should try opening like SIPP’s or investment ISA’s so it’s like being able to access the money-saving experts’ recommendation on accounts to open but it’s all in the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t confident with sharing your banking details with an app, I recommend using spreadsheets as you could replicate what these applications do however, you have to manually enter the transactions that have taken place on each of your accounts into the spreadsheets. When budgeting please take into account monthly subscriptions, direct debits and standing orders and compare whether there are any unnecessary expenses that you can cancel and if there are any subscriptions you can remove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, try to identify all monthly outgoing expenses. This includes the total amount of money used for subscriptions and bills, amount of money for eating out, entertainment, grocery shopping, personal care, general shopping and transportation. You should also try to factor in any expenses for enjoyment like drinking or clubbing. Also, be aware of the amount of money you spend during fresher’s week at university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, try to reduce your spending so that you have more money to spend on important things. Freshers only last a week or 2, spending most of your maintenance during freshers could leave you without money for food or rent. Try to see if you can bring down any of your expenses. For example, if you have multiple streaming services and only use Netflix maybe get rid of the other subscriptions. For your phone bill try to see if you can get a better deal from somewhere else for example, if you only use data and don’t need to get the latest phone all the time maybe go on a pay monthly or pay as you go sim instead of a contract. Also, if you have an unlimited plan for data but only use 10GB, check if it’s cheaper to switch to a 10GB plan with your current provider or a different one. To save more money, learn to cook so that you don’t spend so much money on take away and try shopping at Aldi or Lidl and try using non branded items as they may be as good as branded items but cheaper. Also, if you’re going out to drink or going clubbing try pre-drinking so that you don’t spend so much and taking public transport or walking instead of getting taxis or Ubers could save you quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your living at home or worried about your family’s expenses try to bring down their payments for broadband, gas and electricity. With broadband providers, if you get a landline with your broadband most of the time it is cheaper. Also, if you join money savings expert energy savers club, every 6 months to a year you should compare prices for gas and electricity as new customers get better deals than old. If you want a more autonomous process you could use switchd.co.uk between £0-5 per month to switch you to the cheapest gas and electricity provider, the site tries to save you at least £300. I haven’t used swtichd.co.uk but from my experience with the energy savers club, I was able to save nearly half of what my parents were paying on gas and electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After bringing down your expenses, see how much of the money in your current account you could save. For example, if I have a budget of £500 every month but my total expenses for bills, eating out, entertainment, groceries, shopping, transportation and subscriptions total to £300, you could save £200. This will give you a rough idea of how much money you will be able to save each month then decide how much of that money will go out each month into each of the accounts you choose to set up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Living at Home vs Accommodation</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/living-at-home-vs-accommodation/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:12:23 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/living-at-home-vs-accommodation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Living in accommodation allows you to make new friends at university faster and will allow you to develop more individuality while attending university, however, I decided to stay at home. This allowed to me save money so that I can use my money for other things such as investments, emergency funds and if I need to do any shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things you need to consider when moving into accommodation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you cook?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you comfortable with sharing spaces with other people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is more important to you, your experience at university or saving money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the campus near your home (within an hour on the train)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m more comfortable living at home than at university and I still share the same experiences as my friends at student accommodation. The only downside to living at home is that you are still living with your parents and might have to wake up early to travel to university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving out could be more beneficial as you would be able to develop a greater sense of character and would be more grownup, however, I would rather wait and save up the money to move out of my parents’ home when I have a good job and stable income where purchasing property will not cripple me with debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living at home may not be an option for you if the university you go to is too far away from home and a journey to the campus may take too long on public transport. It depends on whether you prioritize the experience of being at university or saving money but nothing is stopping you from living at university and trying to save as much money as you can. Living in accommodation can also be very convenient as you don’t have to get up early to get to university and there are generally lots of shops within walking distance of the accommodation which will be helpful when trying to buy groceries or any shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Tuition Fee and Maintenance Loan</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/tuition-fee-and-maintenance-loan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:07:39 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/tuition-fee-and-maintenance-loan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of students worry about the tuition fee loan and the maintenance loan as it is a form of debt but it’s not a bad type of debt to have. It’s a loan but it’s not treated like all other types of debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Martin Lewis, the creator of money savings expert, shows that if you are £50000 in debt when you leave university from taking both the maximum tuition and maintenance loans, how much you repay depends on the job you get after university. If you earn a lot after university then you pay back a lot, if you don’t earn a lot after university you don’t pay as much. You only repay 9% of everything you earn above £26500. Money savings expert has explained this in more detail but if you don’t have a high paying job you don’t pay that much back and if you have a high paying job after university, the 9% repayment of everything above £26500 should barely affect you, assuming you don’t spend more than you earn in a year. After 30 years all the remaining debt is wiped and even within the 30 years, most people will never pay all of the loan back. To be precise the 30 years starts from when you start to pay the loan off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student loans aren’t considered like traditional debt where there will be debt collectors trying to get you to make payments on time and the student loans don’t appear on your credit file so applying for loans in the future won’t be affected by the £50000 debt accumulated by going to university. If you choose to you can also pay off the student loans early but I don’t believe it’s necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend taking the student loan and tuition fee loan as it will allow students to attend university without the stress of having to have the £9250 plus the money needed to live in accommodation or at home every year. This means you can choose to get a part-time job and ensures that you can dedicate more time to studying for your degree instead of working to pay off a degree that you haven’t secured yet. I would prioritize working towards completing your degree so you can get the best job you can and then paying off the student loan. This will probably relieve some stress while attending university and will allow you to focus on more important things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do consider getting the tuition fee and maintenance loan I suggest applying for them quite early as this will ensure that you can get the maximum possible when applying for the loans as those who apply late will either get less funding than other students for their maintenance or will receive their maintenance later than other students (the tuition fee loan is not affected if you apply late as long as your application is processed before starting at university). You can apply for them before you have decided which university you’re going to attend as you can change where the money for the tuition fee is paid to by calling student finance and telling them which university has confirmed your placement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How To Decide Between an Apprenticeship or Working Part Time</title>
        <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-decide-between-an-apprenticeship-or-working-part-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:01:09 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-decide-between-an-apprenticeship-or-working-part-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of benefits to apprenticeships and part-time jobs but I would like to discuss which is best for you while attending university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apprenticeships were introduced as a way for students to attend University and not be worried about not being able to afford to go to University as you would be earning money from your job while studying for your degree. However, this is very similar to a student getting a part-time job alongside university as you could use the income from your part-time job towards tuition fees. The main difference between apprenticeships and part-time jobs is that apprenticeships give your hands-on experience into the job sector that you applied for whilst a part-time job won’t give you any specialized experienced in the field you want to work in unless it’s a part-time job associated to what you want to work as when you are out of university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start university, you may already know what type of job you want to get but starting university with virtually no idea where I want to work or what type of job I wanted to get, I completely knew that apprenticeships aren’t for me. If there is anything that you should take away from this chapter it would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONLY DO APPRENTICESHIPS IF ITS FOR THE JOB YOU WANT OR IN THE SECTOR YOU WANT TO WORK IN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do an apprenticeship but you shouldn’t if your only reason is that you can’t afford to go to university. Everyone can afford to go to university and I will explain why in my next chapter but the only reason a student should take an apprenticeship is if it’s in the company or business that you want to work at or if it’s in a similar sector as the job you want to get after completing university.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
