<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Repository on K5924&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://k5924.github.io/categories/repository/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Repository on K5924&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:45:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k5924.github.io/categories/repository/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elevation</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/elevation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:45:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/elevation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  We are provided with a working application that searches a raster of elevation data for regions of relative flatness. The raster is an image in which each pixel represents an elevation for a point on the terrain. The application can be imagined to be searching for potential landing sites for an aircraft or spacecraft of some kind. rgbelevation contains example images to use with the program
 SearchUIEnhancement   Parallelisation   Considerations  All code must implement thread-safety correctly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vault</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/the-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:40:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/the-vault/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  This is an offline password manager as most online password managers store a users information on centralized servers. This gives an end user the ability to take control of how there data is being used and allows end users&#39; to keep hold of their private data whilst interacting with a password manager with an easy to use interface. This project was made for coursework while i was in my 2nd Year of studying Computer Science at LSBU for the Software Engineering module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DiscreteMaths</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/discretemaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:35:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/discretemaths/</guid>
      <description>CourseWork for Discrete MathematicsThe write up will be uploaded to this branch when the coursework has been markedThe file titled linear programming problem.ipynb is an anaconda notebook that i used to run all of the python scripts i have made.LPP The file titled lpp.py is the program i used to build the linear programming graphs of each individual edge in the tree.Graph Theory The file titled dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algo.py is the algorithm used in the graph theory sectionStatistics The basic information files and the pdf files with the csv&amp;rsquo;s are used in this section for the boxplots, gaussian distributions and the probability density functions</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
