<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on K5924&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://k5924.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on K5924&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:45:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k5924.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Elevation</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/elevation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:45:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/elevation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  We are provided with a working application that searches a raster of elevation data for regions of relative flatness. The raster is an image in which each pixel represents an elevation for a point on the terrain. The application can be imagined to be searching for potential landing sites for an aircraft or spacecraft of some kind. rgbelevation contains example images to use with the program
 SearchUIEnhancement    Run the search on a worker thread so the UI doesnt freeze -Display output from the searcher in the text area under the raster A user can cancel the operation and quit the program by closing the window A user can cancel the operation without quitting the program through a cancel button A progress bar is updated each second by a dedicated thread that monitors the progress of the search  Parallelisation    Make a class that extends recursive action which searches the raster for points of elevation Implement a compute method to make new threads in the fork join pool Discard information and update messages from the search listener  Considerations  All code must implement thread-safety correctly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vault</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/the-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:40:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/the-vault/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  This is an offline password manager as most online password managers store a users information on centralized servers. This gives an end user the ability to take control of how there data is being used and allows end users&#39; to keep hold of their private data whilst interacting with a password manager with an easy to use interface. This project was made for coursework while i was in my 2nd Year of studying Computer Science at LSBU for the Software Engineering module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DiscreteMaths</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/discretemaths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:35:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/discretemaths/</guid>
      <description>CourseWork for Discrete MathematicsThe write up will be uploaded to this branch when the coursework has been markedThe file titled linear programming problem.ipynb is an anaconda notebook that i used to run all of the python scripts i have made.LPP The file titled lpp.py is the program i used to build the linear programming graphs of each individual edge in the tree.Graph Theory The file titled dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s algo.py is the algorithm used in the graph theory sectionStatistics The basic information files and the pdf files with the csv&amp;rsquo;s are used in this section for the boxplots, gaussian distributions and the probability density functions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a programming language</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/choosing-a-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 03:19:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/choosing-a-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>Although I will be talking about high level languages I think this post applies to all types of programming languages.
When programming everyone struggles to choose a specific programming language to code in but choosing a language to code in is easier than it seems. In my experience choosing a language mainly depends on what you want to do for the coding project you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen.
For instance, if you are making a CLI application, there is no need to use a language like python or java as it adds unnecessary overhead to the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Investing Works</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-investing-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:17:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-investing-works/</guid>
      <description>I recommend a student account as there are many deals on overdrafts that students can get and many banks provide students incentives to use their student account, if you already have a bank account you can most likely just upgrade your account to a student account with your current bank either over the phone or in branch, this will not affect your bank account details so if you are being paid by student finance into this account their shouldn’t be an issue with the payments going into the account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Budget</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:14:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-budget/</guid>
      <description>You need to set up a budget if you expect to have your maintenance last until the end of the year. I recommend either using apps or spreadsheets. The apps I would recommend are Emma or Money Dashboard. They both offer the same features as they track how much you spend and pulls all or most of your financial accounts into a single place so you can view all of the money coming in and going out each month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living at Home vs Accommodation</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/living-at-home-vs-accommodation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:12:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/living-at-home-vs-accommodation/</guid>
      <description>Living in accommodation allows you to make new friends at university faster and will allow you to develop more individuality while attending university, however, I decided to stay at home. This allowed to me save money so that I can use my money for other things such as investments, emergency funds and if I need to do any shopping.
Things you need to consider when moving into accommodation:
 Can you cook?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuition Fee and Maintenance Loan</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/tuition-fee-and-maintenance-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:07:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/tuition-fee-and-maintenance-loan/</guid>
      <description>Lots of students worry about the tuition fee loan and the maintenance loan as it is a form of debt but it’s not a bad type of debt to have. It’s a loan but it’s not treated like all other types of debt.
Martin Lewis, the creator of money savings expert, shows that if you are £50000 in debt when you leave university from taking both the maximum tuition and maintenance loans, how much you repay depends on the job you get after university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Decide Between an Apprenticeship or Working Part Time</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-decide-between-an-apprenticeship-or-working-part-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:01:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-decide-between-an-apprenticeship-or-working-part-time/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of benefits to apprenticeships and part-time jobs but I would like to discuss which is best for you while attending university.
Apprenticeships were introduced as a way for students to attend University and not be worried about not being able to afford to go to University as you would be earning money from your job while studying for your degree. However, this is very similar to a student getting a part-time job alongside university as you could use the income from your part-time job towards tuition fees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
