<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on K5924&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://k5924.github.io/categories/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on K5924&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:17:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://k5924.github.io/categories/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Investing Works</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-investing-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:17:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-investing-works/</guid>
      <description>I recommend a student account as there are many deals on overdrafts that students can get and many banks provide students incentives to use their student account, if you already have a bank account you can most likely just upgrade your account to a student account with your current bank either over the phone or in branch, this will not affect your bank account details so if you are being paid by student finance into this account their shouldn’t be an issue with the payments going into the account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Budget</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:14:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-budget/</guid>
      <description>You need to set up a budget if you expect to have your maintenance last until the end of the year. I recommend either using apps or spreadsheets. The apps I would recommend are Emma or Money Dashboard. They both offer the same features as they track how much you spend and pulls all or most of your financial accounts into a single place so you can view all of the money coming in and going out each month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living at Home vs Accommodation</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/living-at-home-vs-accommodation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:12:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/living-at-home-vs-accommodation/</guid>
      <description>Living in accommodation allows you to make new friends at university faster and will allow you to develop more individuality while attending university, however, I decided to stay at home. This allowed to me save money so that I can use my money for other things such as investments, emergency funds and if I need to do any shopping.
Things you need to consider when moving into accommodation:
 Can you cook?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuition Fee and Maintenance Loan</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/tuition-fee-and-maintenance-loan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:07:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/tuition-fee-and-maintenance-loan/</guid>
      <description>Lots of students worry about the tuition fee loan and the maintenance loan as it is a form of debt but it’s not a bad type of debt to have. It’s a loan but it’s not treated like all other types of debt.
Martin Lewis, the creator of money savings expert, shows that if you are £50000 in debt when you leave university from taking both the maximum tuition and maintenance loans, how much you repay depends on the job you get after university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Decide Between an Apprenticeship or Working Part Time</title>
      <link>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-decide-between-an-apprenticeship-or-working-part-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 01:01:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://k5924.github.io/p/how-to-decide-between-an-apprenticeship-or-working-part-time/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of benefits to apprenticeships and part-time jobs but I would like to discuss which is best for you while attending university.
Apprenticeships were introduced as a way for students to attend University and not be worried about not being able to afford to go to University as you would be earning money from your job while studying for your degree. However, this is very similar to a student getting a part-time job alongside university as you could use the income from your part-time job towards tuition fees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
